I'm on my way to the Amphi Festival and was here yesterday and today in the backstage.
I looked who I would meet, who I could chat with a little bit and it was pretty funny.
So have fun with the video and I can only recommend it to everyone who comes to the Amphi.
I'm here with Marc Benecke. How many years have you been moderating the Amphi?
Christian, nobody knows anymore. I was already a guest at the very first Amphi Festival, as a
Christian, nobody knows me anymore. I was already a guest at the very first Amphi Festival as a
and now I can walk around backstage. But I actually belong, I think.
Are you better off on stage for a lecture or as a moderator to announce the others?
So as a moderator, you can get a little out of it, but the bands are
also keen to be announced, what do they want to hear and so on. They also become relaxed over the years.
That's very interesting, they become more relaxed. If you're on stage yourself, you have to
concentrate a little more. As a moderator you can do a lot of fax.
Okay, I can already hear you're just here to have fun.
Amphi or WGT?
Can you compare? WGT is the East Festival in this huge agra hall, in these super many small clubs, where the sweat really dries from the ceiling.
But really now, seriously, no joke. And here it's all a bit more civilized in the city and not so many different places.
There is no alcohol backstage, except you order it extra.
Ah, okay, thanks for the tip!
Well, I think both are good.
How long are you still doing the job?
Like Roland Kaiser, like Howard Carpendale, like everyone else, as long as the audience wants it.
Like Thomas Gottschalk, as long as the audience wants it.
Then have fun, what are you going to be recording?
Next up is Welle Erdball, guys.
A super, super, mega cool band. Without them, the scene wouldn't be in this form.
They're playing in the living room today. I thought they didn't like it.
That was a pre-conversation. I asked them if I should say something.
They said it was stupid and they said it was super cool. We've been waiting for 10, 20 years.
I saw them on the ship last year, at the pre-party.
On the ship, at the pre-party. I've seen Hanni before.
He didn't perform at the WGT once.
He had an iPod Nano or something.
He plugged it in. Oh, hello.
Hello.
Spock, the band Spock.
and then just performed in some kind of absurd store and so it is still on at WGT.
Cool, then thank you very much and have fun working.
And if you want to win an iPod Nano, then call 0800 Amphifestival.
Thank you, see you again. Bye.
Hi Chris.
Hi Sophie.
Nice that you took the time.
You will be on stage later with Lord of the Lost?
Yes, exactly, in 5-6 hours.
Okay, and you will be on stage with Lord of the Lost.
You will be on stage with Lord of the Lost later.
Yes, exactly, in 5-6 hours.
Okay, and I now have a short slot for the interview. Thank you very much.
I asked a few either or questions.
Oh please, I'm in pretty bad shape.
So short questions, short answers.
Festival or club performances?
Today festival, because I always assume what is important to me on that day.
Better to live Jet Set Tour or at home?
At home.
At home?
Yes.
Are you now, do you have enough from touring?
I'm always at home. I love being on stage at that moment. But all this traveling around and being away from home and waiting all day and everything is always chaotic is not mine.
I love being a musician, being on stage at that moment. I need everything else around me.
Who is the better president? Icke Hüftgold or Marc Benecke?
Marc Benecke for sure. So nothing against Icke. We got along well. Sorry Icke, but Marc Benecke.
I even tattooed an M for Marc.
Oh really?
Oh shit, where is the ugly dolphin?
I had a stupid bet with Marc.
Marc tattooed the M himself.
And that's the little dolphin, that's our partner tattoo.
He also has a blue banana.
Yesterday he was thinking about tattooing my signature, so I have to sign it on his neck with his filler.
So just on the neck.
Who makes the outfits for you?
Very different. I sew them myself. I'm a Waldorf student and know how to use a sewing machine.
But I haven't done that for years. The question is which outfits. Do you have any special ones?
No, in general. You wear something different all the time. I see that.
We work with all these black clothes that we often wore now. Also with the ESC, red carpet and so on.
It's Minois. That's a very cool, very cool, cool, very cool, Bulgarian small company.
But most of it is actually composed of, I don't know,
Orsay girls' department up to Zara, mostly women's department.
You take a dress, you think it glitters cool, you cut it down a bit, you have a cool top.
Do you then fix it and tell the others what to wear or should everyone decide for themselves?
In principle, everyone should decide for themselves, but sometimes I make a concept,
a general optical one for certain performances.
But of course we always talk about it.
It's not like I say, you're wearing this now, I don't like that.
Everyone should feel comfortable.
It's very different.
But we managed to fit in well with each other.
It's very funny.
It's a life of its own.
What's your favorite outfit at the moment?
I'm really into paint right now.
I haven't found it interesting for years.
I don't have a latex fetish.
I think it looks so incredibly cool on stage, especially in the headlights.
I like paint on stage very much.
You saw that at the ESC. Also red paint.
I saw the video for the first time and thought, what's that?
That's actually my first top part, which was re-sewn a bit.
I bought that on Ebay for a lot of money.
We actually had a designer for an ESC, Corinna Mikschel from Munich.
We casted them. We made a call for the whole Blood & Glitter era before the album.
We're looking for a designer who knows and understands Lord of the Lost.
And we wanted to try something new. We said we wanted to make a glam rock album.
And then we developed it with her. We told her what we want, what we don't want.
Then she did the typical drawing and then we adapted it.
How many makeup tutorials have you watched on YouTube to make your stage makeup?
Not a single one.
Not a single one? Is it just trial and error or how does it all happen?
I don't know, I'm 43 now. When did I start putting on make-up? 30 years ago.
In school for the first time, with eyeliner, 28, 15 or so.
It will come at some point.
So actually never. Sometimes it is actually like that, that you see a photo and think, wow, that's cool.
Or you look at something like Germany's Next Topmodel and see these crazy make-up artists and think, wow, that's cool.
That's inspiring.
But we've never done that after a make-up tutorial.
And of course we also have help with the very important performances.
At the ESC we had five makeup artists.
Five?
Yes, each one.
Okay, yes, each one.
The whole day.
It's already a spurt, isn't it? Probably if you don't have to do it yourself.
Yes, of course, of course.
But I mean, it's television.
On television, you see everything.
Everything has to be perfect.
Every second.
Yes, of course.
Many thanks.
Thank you.
We'll see you on the cruise ship.
Yes, hopefully.
See you on stage later. Have fun!
Thanks, bye!
Snow and fire, trading stars
On the horizon
Blue silver thunderbolts
Stone of breath
The warm embrace of facing death
The sweet defiance
Your eyes ignite and diffuse just like diamonds in the blood
I just saw you guys on stage with Comic Christ.
How was it?
First impression after the show?
Where was that?
No, it was good.
It was great.
It's good to be back here.
I mean, this is the first time we do a fully electronic show at Amphia, I think.
So yeah, it was great.
It was fun.
It was a fun show.
Why did you decide to go back to the electronic sets?
I'm curious about that because I've seen you with the whole band and guitars and now it's just the two of you.
It's a 20 year anniversary.
So we kind of just go back and do some of the old stuff.
We do some of the songs of course with the full band.
But it was just cool to do something for ourselves and for the fans for the anniversary.
you know. But I have to say I'm kind of missing Eric. Like I met him on Malta and he was really fun and I was like
Are you two? And he was like no I'm not and I was like okay I'll take you guys then. Yeah, you know it
we're going back on tour again in September October with a full band and
then everybody's gonna be back together and we miss the guys too, you know, but
for now, yay! This is just fun to do something for us and just
it's
It's fun. It's simple. It was how it used to be and
That was the whole point of the anniversary tour was just to do something more
More down-to-earth and and different than what we're used to now
but now we're you know, we're all looking forward to go with a full band and production again and play new songs and
It's just a very different energy, you know, so
This is more dancey and more a EBM and dance stuff in it. And just it's fun
but you know I miss the aggressive heavy stuff so we'll get there we'll get there
back this not your head no yeah this is the first interview I'm doing in English
because all the other bands have been German you know what do you like about
the German festivals why do you keep coming back is there any other festivals
in Europe really except for dark Malta it's like a multi I saw you too I can
of Coil. And what else is there? I think there was one in the Netherlands and in
Belgium or something like that. Yeah, maybe. It used to be so many festivals in
Belgium as well, but there hasn't really been. You're forgetting to nod your head.
No, but what's your favorite thing about Germany and German festivals? I mean, I used to
live here for a while. I lived in Hamburg for three years and, you know, this is kind of
where the band started some way, you know. Like, I started the band living in
Germany. A lot of the stuff that I wrote was from the first album was when I
lived in Germany. Well, all of it when I lived in Germany. And so I kind of know
the scene the best from Germany, you know. So you have a special connection going on. Yeah, a special connection.
It's kind of like where it was, where Combi Christ was born, you know.
The promoters are all family too, right? Yeah. I feel this, like the whole scene is a big family here.
and everyone knows each other and everyone's like hey I mean everybody working this festival is
yeah like family to us yeah I mean family see did he give it to you himself or did you just find it
here sure it was it was passed on to us from Steve yeah yeah no actually Steve is a very
good friend of mine too actually. Yeah it was a monster too so. Yeah no it's like I
said we're all family and I mean Lord of the Lost is on stage now it's you know
again family. Hamburg Digger. Yeah Hamburg Digger. He used to live in Hamburg, I live in Hamburg. They are from Hamburg.
Yeah no so it's that's why it's a was just just one big big I was about to say
happy it's not always happy family but one big family. We gothics we don't be happy. One big sad family.
Miserable. Miserable.
So yeah, no, but it's, no, it's, um, yeah, so it's a special connection to it. And, um, I don't think I spent much time in Germany
over the last 20 years where I haven't been touring, to be honest. I mean, I get, there is, of course, I've been doing,
doing some off days and you do, you know, you go walk around and you do stuff, but
Most of the time we spend here is touring.
But that is our connection here, that is our family here.
How good is your German, Dan?
Schlecht.
Schlechter?
Grammatik is scheiße.
Du verstehst alles, aber...
Okay, at least you understand it, so that's cool.
Alright, thanks for taking the time.
My pleasure, thank you.
And I'll see you, I don't know, where are you heading next?
Um, home.
Home?
Yeah, I'm going home tomorrow.
You know, I live in the US, Vegas.
And so, we're going home tomorrow.
My girlfriend and I are traveling back with Lufthansa again.
Lufthansa!
F*** Lufthansa!
They lost your luggage, I know.
Yeah, they lost my luggage.
I know.
God damn it.
Germany knows.
Yeah.
So, we're coming back?
You're coming back? When's your next Germany gig?
We are starting September 24th, I think.
Something like that.
End of September and October with Megahertz.
Ah, yeah, right.
Yeah, and all over Europe.
And then there will be a little time off working on a new album.
Now I have to finish it because I said it.
You do. I have it on record here.
Yeah, I know.
I'll send it to you like weekly, like there you said it.
It's about time, it's about time.
I never force, you know, I just never force writing a new album.
So it just, it have to be the right time.
And we have, you know, Elliot and I have been writing, I don't know, it's a lot of songs.
So we just kind of have to go through everything and kind of dial in what we want to finish.
That's really...
It's been more like a philosophy session of like, what is a good song?
What is a good song?
I'm looking forward to that and when it's going to be released.
Okay, thanks.
My pleasure.
See you.
Bye.
Every day the brain does the same.
A signal says it's all okay.
We know it's not, it's all that we got.
We're still alive, forgot how to live.
Trying to hang on to this world.
What would you like to see in the future?
Cool, last question.
I already have four minutes for one question.
Then I have to think of five more.
I talk very slowly and philosophize a lot.
I think it's great what you're doing for the scene and that you've shown our scene outside.
What would you like to give our Gothic scene for the future?
I always have a little problem, I'm a little scared that it will get too old.
Yes, so the problem is a good question for the end, because you can talk about it for a long time.
And the thing is, first of all, we are at home in many different scenes.
We are also somehow in the metal scene.
Exactly, I'll see you on Wacken next week again.
We are somehow mainstream, we are somehow glam, we feel totally at home on every Christopher Street Day.
And that's where we actually come to what I think is very good, but what is a problem for many.
Because if you are not just part of this one scene as part of a scene, then that is often a problem.
And every scene comes with a certain dogma and certain rules and do's and don'ts.
And that's where we come to exactly the problem that many, and that's not just in the black scene,
but also in metal and also in rap and no matter where, as soon as you are too far out, also somewhere else,
you are in the worst case a scene traitor or you are just not true or you don't really belong to it
and it is mixed too much and softened and we are no longer just among us and so on and I have to say
that is of course type dependent but I have never felt comfortable with this only we so among us
Because that always limits everything else and I feel different every day.
And look, I'm sitting here with my stuff and wearing my disfavored world hoodie from Swiss with great pride.
And the others that I produce.
Am I allowed to produce something like that as a singer of a gothic metal band, a punk rap troupe?
That's where we come to the question. Is that still true?
Is that still true? Is that still punk rock?
Exactly, exactly, super, this song, is that still punk rock? Exactly, punk, exactly the same.
And they have exactly the same problem.
Swiss and the others are also exactly on this border between mainstream and underground and these are the same discussions in every scene.
What I would wish for would be, if everyone says, we would like to be treated empathetically, be understood and somehow, even though we are outsiders, are still accepted.
then you have to accept this acceptance from the inside.
I think a scene can only develop if you don't hide what's new.
And I have two more minutes.
The thing is, what you hear very often is this thing,
Gothic scene has no offspring, metal scene has no offspring.
Yes, or just the audience.
When you look around at a festival, at a classic, I have to say,
it feels like it's getting older, especially on the WGT I noticed it again.
That's exactly the thing. If you just say, we actually only want Sisters of Mercy and The Cure,
and then new bands come that might be like that, then it means, no, it's a copy.
But then bands come that are completely different, try to blow fresh air into the scene,
and then it means, but that's not like The Cure. And that's where the problem comes in.
And then it might be like that, maybe when all of this collapses,
then maybe at some point the black scene 2.0 will emerge from itself.
We can only hope.
Exactly. I would just like to be open and not lose the fun in the matter.
Because we don't wear black because we all want to die and are so unhappy, but because we feel so comfortable, because it's a positive feeling.
I actually just wrote a song about it, about wearing this black for our next album, somewhere in 2025.
You know it all from the shirt, the black is my happy color.
What I want to say is that we are here in the black scene to have fun.
And fun has a lot to do with openness.
That's not my thing. I would like to be open.
But are you allowed to be on the Wacken on 70,000 tons of metal if you are here on the black scene?
I just do it.
Yes, you do it. But are you confronted with something like that?
That you jump too far between the chairs?
Actually less, because I'm mainly in the fashion scene.
That's even worse.
Yes, but I apparently found the niche there.
You see, you're not cool at all. You're just here because of fashion.
Exactly.
But it's an interesting discussion.
You have to make sure that you also get comments like that.
Actually, I have little problems with negative comments.
That's mostly envy anyway.
So the most important thing I've learned, maybe I've taken over that from myself for five seconds,
is that everything you get in negative comments is actually just about the commentators.
Yes, anyway.
In any case, that's also true.
All right. Thank you very much.